A useful evaluation metric is the rank information coefficient,
排名信息系数是一个很有用的评估指标
often referred to as rank IC.
经常称为排名 IC
The rank IC tells us whether the ranks of
排名 IC 可以告诉我们
our alpha values are correlated with the ranks of the future returns.
alpha 值的排名是否与未来收益率的排名相关
In other words, if the alpha factor suggested that we bet
换句话说 如果 alpha 因子表明
more on stock ABC and less on stock XYZ,
我们对股票 ABC 看涨 对 XYZ 看跌
was the future return of ABC relatively high?
ABC 的未来收益率相对更高吗？
Was a future return of stock XYZ relatively low?
XYZ 的未来收益率相对更低吗？
If the future performance of the assets matched
如果资产的未来业绩与
the expectations that was suggested by the alpha factor,
alpha 因子表明的预期相符
then the information coefficient would be higher.
那么信息系数更高
Otherwise, it would be lower and possibly negative.
否则更低 可能为负
For some insight, let's first look at this without ranking.
下面看看没有排名的股票
Let's pretend there are just two stocks in our universe, ABC and XYZ.
假设股票池中有两个股票 ABC 和 XYZ
Stock ABC has a high positive alpha value and
股票 ABC 具有很高的正 alpha 值
XYZ has a very negative alpha value as calculated before time,
XYZ 具有很低的负 alpha 值 都是在 t 之前计算的
t. Between time T to time T plus one,
从 t 到 t+1
the return of stock ABC is positive and XYZ's return is negative.
ABC 的收益率为正 XYZ 的收益率为负
These alpha values appear to be correlated with the forward asset returns.
这些 alpha 值似乎与远期资产收益率相关
Note here, when we say asset return,
注意 我们提到的资产收益率
we're referring to the return of each stock for each time period.
是指每个股票在每个时段的收益率
We also specify that the asset return is a forward return.
我们还指定资产收益率是远期收益率
We say, forward asset return to specify that the return is in
远期收益率是指与 alpha 值的计算时间相比
the future or forward in time compared to when the alpha value was calculated.
收益率是未来或远期的收益率
So, if the alpha values are calculated before time t,
如果 alpha 值是在时间 t 之前计算的
then the forward asset return is calculated with data that
那么远期资产收益率是用
occurs later from time t to time t plus one.
之后（从 t 到 t+1）的数据计算的
To make our evaluation more robust,
为了使评估结果更可靠
we want to use ranks instead of the original alpha values and returns.
我们将使用排名数据 而不使用原始 alpha 值和收益率
Stock ABC is alpha value before time t is high and positive,
股票 ABC 的 alpha 值在时间 t 之前是很高的正数
while stock XYZ is alpha value, is negative.
而stock XYZ 的 alpha 值为负
So, ABC has a higher rank of two and XYZ has a lower rank of one.
所以 ABC 的排名更高 为 2 而 XYZ 的排名更低 为 1
The forward asset return of ABC from time t to time t plus one is higher compared to XYZ.
ABC 从时间 t 到 t+1 的远期资产收益率比 XYZ 的高
So, the rank of ABC's forward asset return is two,
所以 ABC 的远期资产收益率为 2
and the rank of XYZ's forward asset return is one.
而 XYZ 的远期资产收益率为 1
If the ranks of the alpha values and the ranks
如果 alpha 值的排名与
of the forward asset returns are highly correlated,
远期资产收益率的排名高度相关
the rank IC metric would be close to one.
那么排名 IC 接近 1
In this example, since the ranks of
在此示例中
the two alpha values are equal to the ranks of the two forward asset returns,
因为两个 alpha 值的排名等于两个远期资产收益率的排名
then the rank IC in this example is one.
所以排名 IC 等于 1